

NICHOLAS KATO

Full Stack Developer

Kaidechō, Shinotsubo-1, Kyoto 617-0004 <u>niclas.kato92@gmail.com</u> / +81 050-5806-8992 / <u>https://niclaskato-intro.vercel.app</u>

SUMMARY

Offering 7+ years of progressive experience in owning web-based projects from concept and design through testing, implementation, and updates. Diligent about producing especially clean, strong, and secure code. Successful at achieving browser, device, and operating system compatibility objectives while satisfying client desires and producing robust, sophisticated designs. Outgoing and friendly with strong motivation for success.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Science: Computer Science

Kyoto University - Kyoto, Japan

09/2014

SKILLS

- Front-End Frameworks: React, Next, Vue, Angular
- Back-End Frameworks: Nest, Express, Django
- Version Control Systems: Git, GitHub, GitLab
- Scripting Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python
- Web Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- Material UI, Chakra UI, Styled components
- Web3.js/Ethers.js
- Mocha/Chai
- Firebase
- Google ads, Google Cloud, AWS
- RESTful API

- Team Work: Jira, Trello, Asana
- Interpersonal Skills
- Analytical Thinking
- Complex Problem Solving
- Agile Software Development
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Creativity and Innovation
- Web Architecture
- Time Management and Prioritization
- Project Management
- Oral and Written Communications

EXPERIENCE

React Front-end Engineer / Sitback Solutions - Sydney, Australia / Remote

03/2021 - 06/2022

- Improved and designed new layouts to achieve usability and performance objectives.
- Utilized React, React hook, and Material UI front-end web application for a real estate tax calculation throughout development phases.
- Designed user authentication and Firestore data manipulation with Node.js back-end Firebase cloud functions for multiple clients.
- Added Firestore and storage security rules for the database and storage access management.
- Supported continuous improvement by investigating alternatives and technologies for review.

- Designed robust, scalable, secure, and globalized web-based applications to ensure the continuity of all business processes and client satisfaction.
- Running web and application servers in the cloud to host dynamic websites using Amazon Web Service AWS.
- Developed, tested, and debugged software tools utilized by 100+ clients and internal customers to facilitate and easier process and user experience.
- Used the Python and Nest.js to develop 3 web-based data retrieval systems.
- Performed data entry and other clerical work for project completion.
- Obtained adequate experience in reviewing Python code for running the troubleshooting test-cases and bug issues, acquiring all necessary skills.

React & Vue Front-end Engineer / Konica Minolta - Kyoto, JP / Hybrid

11/2017 - 12/2019

- Built a custom web crawler that downloads 1.5 billion images from the web while optimizing resources and execution time.
- Delivered front-end code for Ascribe, to meet functional or technical specifications.
- Evaluated and implemented interface tests to maximize development efficiency.
- Composed and optimized the back-end code from queries to execution time.
- Constructed a high-performance reverse-search engine called image-match.

Front-end JavaScript Developer / DIGITAL GUARDIAN - Massachusetts, US / Remote

08/2015 - 05/2017

- Improved and designed new layouts to achieve usability and performance objectives.
- Developed UIs using ReactJS with JavaScript and TypeScript.
- Securely stored all public server files on the cloud using AWS, so everyone can comprehensively access them from anywhere.
- Participated in the full lifecycle of development for the company's web applications using JS framework, including React and Vue.
- Maintained and improved the client portal React application.

INTERESTS

- Artificial Intelligence
- Writing Blogs
- Team or individual sports